♪I'd rather soar like a mayfly in another dimension♪
♪ أفضل التحليق مثل ذبابة مايو في بعد آخر
♪Restart my life and gaze at the rainbow together♪
♪ أعد تشغيل حياتي وحدق في قوس قزح معًا
♪I do not regret my promise to you♪
♪ لست نادمًا على وعدي لك
=My Deepest Dream=
= أعمق حلمي =
Yu,
يو ،
I'll marry you, okay?
انا اتزوجك اتفقنا
(Some people say it's lucky to see the future.)
(يقول بعض الناس إنه محظوظ لرؤية المستقبل).
(While some say)
(بينما يقول البعض)
(it's a curse to see the future.)
(إنها لعنة أن ترى المستقبل).
(But I believe the flow of time)
(لكنني أؤمن بتدفق الوقت)
(can bring meaning to life.)
(يمكن أن يضفي معنى على الحياة).
(In the flow of time,)
(في تدفق الوقت)
(we can own a permanent coordinate.)
(يمكننا امتلاك إحداثي دائم.)
(I feel)
(انا اشعر)
(very lucky.)
(محظوظ جدا.)
=Episode 22=
= الحلقة 22 =
Don't move!
لا تتحرك!
Stay still!
اثبت مكانك!
Don't come any closer.
لا تقترب أكثر.
Chen Xingjian,
تشن شينغ جيان
there's nowhere to run now.
لا يوجد مكان للركض الآن.
Don't come any closer.
لا تقترب أكثر.
If you do, all of us will die together!
إذا قمت بذلك ، فسوف نموت جميعًا معًا!
Take him away.
يأخذه بعيدا.
Yes, Sir!
نعم سيدي!
Wu Yu,
وو يو ،
this is what I saw.
هذا ما رأيته.
We've finally caught him.
لقد أمسكنا به أخيرًا.
(Wu Yu)
(وو يو)
Hello?
مرحبًا؟
Hello, Officer Shen.
مرحبًا ، الضابط شين.
We've caught him.
لقد أمسكنا به.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
Remember to bring Xiaoyu back.
تذكر أن تعيد Xiaoyu.
Don't worry.
لا تقلق.
We've made a promise.
لقد قطعنا وعدًا.
No matter which time and space,
بغض النظر عن الزمان والمكان ،
I'll always love you.
ساحبك دائما.
Be careful.
كن حذرا.
Tan Jiao.
تان جياو.
What?
ماذا؟
Call Tan Jiao for me.
اتصل بتان جياو من أجلي.
Tan Jiao,
تان جياو ،
she wants to talk to you.
تريد التحدث معك.
Xu Jingmiao.
شو جينغمياو.
There's one more person inside.
هناك شخص آخر بالداخل.
Is it another victim?
هل هي ضحية أخرى؟
A perpetrator.
الجاني.
There's another perpetrator.
هناك مرتكب آخر.
Chen Xingjian is not working alone.
تشن شينغ جيان لا يعمل بمفرده.
Take your time and tell me.
خذ وقتك وأخبرني.
What does that person look like?
كيف يبدو هذا الشخص؟
What did he do?
ماذا فعل؟
Where is he now?
أين هو الآن؟
I was half awake.
كنت نصف مستيقظ.
I heard people arguing.
سمعت الناس يتجادلون.
They were very loud.
كانوا صاخبين جدا.
That person's voice is frightening.
صوت هذا الشخص مخيف.
He said...
هو قال...
What did he say?
ماذا قال؟
He said Chen Xingjian's mission is completed.
وقال إن مهمة تشن شينغ جيان قد اكتملت.
He'll take care of Tan Jiao himself.
سوف يعتني بتان جياو بنفسه.
What else
ماذا بعد
did he say after that?
هل قال بعد ذلك؟
Where is he now?
أين هو الآن؟
Xu Jingmiao.
شو جينغمياو.
Chen Xingjian?
تشن شينغ جيان؟
How did you know my name?
كيف عرفت اسمي؟
Don't move!
لا تتحرك!
Don't do anything reckless.
لا تفعل أي شيء متهور.
Even if you killed me,
حتى لو قتلتني
you have nowhere to run.
ليس لديك مكان للجري.
I said, don't move.
قلت لا تتحرك.
Do you want to die?
هل تريد أن تموت؟
Are you okay?
هل انت بخير؟
Wu Yu.
وو يو.
Hurry! Catch him!
عجل!  امسكه!
Stop right there!
توقف هناك!
Let me go!
دعني اذهب!
What do you want by ganging up on me?
ماذا تريد بالتحالف علي؟
Why are you here?
لماذا أنت هنا؟
Who's your accomplice?
من هو شريكك؟
Tell me!
أخبرني!
I...
أنا...
Wu Yu.
وو يو.
What's going on?
ماذا يحدث هنا؟
This man attacked Tan Jiao with a knife
هاجم هذا الرجل تان جياو بسكين
while she was alone.
بينما كانت وحيدة.
Nonsense!
كلام فارغ!
I wanted to save her!
أردت أن أنقذها!
You?
أنت؟
How did you end up here?
كيف انتهى بك الأمر هنا؟
Why can't I be here?
لماذا لا أستطيع أن أكون هنا؟
I met with a shipwreck and fainted.
التقيت بغرق سفينة وأغمي علي.
I was already there when I woke up.
كنت هناك بالفعل عندما استيقظت.
Do you know each other?
هل تعرف بعضكم البعض؟
Yes.
نعم.
His name is Chen Xingjian.
اسمه Chen Xingjian.
We used to have a band together.
اعتدنا أن يكون لدينا فرقة معًا.
We disbanded because of discord.
لقد انفصلنا بسبب الفتنة.
I'm sure it's a misunderstanding.
أنا متأكد من أنه سوء فهم.
Why don't you let him go first?
لماذا لا تدعه يذهب أولا؟
Misunderstanding?
سوء فهم؟
I don't want to be with a traitor like you.
لا أريد أن أكون مع خائن مثلك.
Who are you calling a traitor?
من الذي تسميه بالخائن؟
Someone unknown in the past
شخص غير معروف في الماضي
who'd do anything for money.
من سيفعل أي شيء مقابل المال.
Say that again.
قل ذلك مرة أخرى.
Enough!
كافية!
Why did you attack Tan Jiao?
لماذا هاجمت تان جياو؟
Are the two missing girls related
هل الفتاتان المفقودتان مرتبطتان
to you?
لك؟
What two girls?
ما فتاتان؟
Are you guys...
هل انتم شباب...
Tell us.
أخبرنا.
Okay.
تمام.
You're ganging up on me because I'm outnumbered, huh?
أنت تحاربني لأنني فاق العدد ، أليس كذلك؟
Fine.
بخير.
I wanted to kill her.
كنت أرغب في قتلها.
I also captured those two girls.
أنا أيضا أسرت هاتين الفتاتين.
What are you going to do about it?
ما انت ذاهب الى القيام به حيال ذلك؟
- Hey! - Calm down.
- يا!  - هدء من روعك.
- Where are they now? - Stop it!
- أين هم الآن؟  - توقف عن ذلك!
Are you going to tell us or not?
هل ستخبرنا أم لا؟
You're going to rough me up, huh?
أنت ستضربني بخشونة ، أليس كذلك؟
I caught them for fun.
أمسكت بهم من أجل المتعة.
So? Are you going to kill me?
لذا؟  هل ستقتلني؟
Stop it.
توقف عن ذلك.
Wait.
انتظر.
Are you okay?
هل انت بخير؟
I'm fine.
أنا بخير.
You wanted
انت اردت
to kill the snake with the knife, right?
لقتل الثعبان بالسكين ، أليس كذلك؟
You're so imaginative.
أنت مبدع جدا.
I wanted to kill you.
أردت قتلك.
It killed the snake
قتلت الثعبان
by mistake.
عن طريق الخطأ.
That's enough.
هذا يكفي.
Everyone, please calm down.
الجميع ، يرجى الهدوء.
Don't be agitated.
لا تنزعج.
We can talk nicely about this.
يمكننا التحدث بلطف عن هذا.
Excuse me, mister.
معذرة سيد.
Where's my daughter?
اين ابنتي
Your daughter
ابنتك
may be...
ربما...
She may be dead.
قد تكون ميتة.
Stop talking nonsense.
توقف عن الكلام هراء.
Mom!
أم!
Ying!
يينغ!
Did you call me?
هل اتصلت بي
Ying,
ينغ ،
where have you been?
اين كنت؟
You scared me!
لقد أخفتني!
Excuse me.
اعذرني.
Why are you alone?
لماذا انت وحيد؟
Isn't Miss Zhu Jirui
Isn't Miss Zhu Jirui
with you?
معك؟
Did you see her?
هل رأيتها؟
Miss Zhu?
ملكة جمال تشو؟
Yes.
نعم.
She's just in front.
انها فقط في المقدمة.
Do you want me to take you there?
هل تريدني أن آخذك إلى هناك؟
Let's go.
لنذهب.
Be careful.
كن حذرا.
Over here.
هنا.
She's there.
انها هناك.
Rui,
روي ،
are you okay?
انت بخير؟
- Are you hurt? - I'm fine.
- هل تأذيت؟  - أنا بخير.
I'm not hurt.
أنا لا أتألم.
What about you guys?
ماذا عنك الرجال؟
We're fine.
نحن بخير.
We've been looking for you by the beach.
كنا نبحث عنك على الشاطئ.
Mom,
أم،
you're unbelievable.
أنت غير معقول.
I only wanted to be alone for a while.
أردت فقط أن أكون وحدي لفترة من الوقت.
Do you need to make a fuss about this?
هل تحتاج إلى إثارة ضجة حول هذا؟
It's embarrassing.
إنه محرج.
Do you know I was worried sick about you?
هل تعلم أنني كنت قلقة عليك؟
How could you go off without telling anyone?
كيف يمكنك أن تنطلق دون أن تخبر أحداً؟
You're too insensible.
أنت غير مدرك للغاية.
What?
ماذا؟
We were only here for half an hour.
مكثنا هنا لمدة نصف ساعة فقط.
We're not kids here.
نحن لسنا أطفالًا هنا.
Half an hour?
نصف ساعه؟
Are you mad?
هل انت مجنون؟
Everyone had been looking for you two
كان الجميع يبحث عنكما
all day.
طوال اليوم.
He's right.
إنه على حق.
We were worried about you guys.
كنا قلقين بشأنكم يا رفاق.
Why do you have to say that?
لماذا عليك أن تقول ذلك؟
She was with me too.
كانت معي ايضا
What's wrong with two adults coming out
ما الخطأ في خروج شخصين بالغين
for a walk?
للتمشي؟
Are you saying
هل تقول
you only left the campsite
لقد غادرت موقع المخيم فقط
for half an hour?
لمدة نصف ساعة؟
Tan Jiao, what do you mean by that?
تان جياو ، ماذا تقصد بذلك؟
Are you saying we're lying?
هل تقول أننا نكذب؟
Keep quiet.
الزم الصمت.
She wasn't in a good mood.
لم تكن في مزاج جيد.
So I comforted her.
لذلك أرتحتها.
We really didn't take too much time.
لم نأخذ الكثير من الوقت حقًا.
Look at this.
انظر إلى هذا.
Are you behind this?
هل انت وراء هذا؟
Do you think I'm capable of that?
هل تعتقد أنني قادر على ذلك؟
Could this be a special species?
هل يمكن أن يكون هذا نوعًا خاصًا؟
I don't think it's the species.
لا أعتقد أنها الأنواع.
There's no plant that blooms and withers
لا يوجد نبات يزهر ويذبل
in such a short time.
في مثل هذا الوقت القصير.
We saw many of these over there.
لقد رأينا الكثير من هؤلاء هناك.
Let's check them out.
دعونا نتحقق منها.
Be gentle.
كن لطيفآ.
It's pretty.
إنه جميل.
Don't be scared.
لا تخف.
No ghost comes out during the day.
لا شبح يخرج خلال النهار.
Huh?
هاه؟
What's wrong?
ما هو الخطأ؟
I know what's going on now.
أعرف ما الذي يحدث الآن.
Check the time.
تحقق من الوقت.
Wait for me.
الانتظار لي.
Wu Yu.
وو يو.
Yu.
يو.
How long did it take?
كم من الوقت استغرقت؟
It's been seven seconds.
لقد مرت سبع ثوان.
I spent two minutes there.
قضيت دقيقتين هناك.
The flowers didn't bloom quicker,
الزهور لم تتفتح بشكل أسرع ،
or people walked faster.
أو مشى الناس أسرع.
The time is the issue here.
الوقت هو القضية هنا.
The time doesn't flow regularly.
الوقت لا يتدفق بانتظام.
Miss Zhu and Ying's
ملكة جمال تشو وينغ
half-hour stay there
البقاء هناك لمدة نصف ساعة
is equivalent to half a day here.
ما يعادل نصف يوم هنا.
See? I told you.
نرى؟  أخبرتك.
I wasn't lying.
لم أكن أكذب.
This situation doesn't happen by accident.
هذا الموقف لا يحدث بالصدفة.
Time is affected by energy.
الوقت يتأثر بالطاقة.
So I'm guessing this island has a unique magnetic field,
لذلك أعتقد أن هذه الجزيرة لديها مجال مغناطيسي فريد ،
which is powerful enough to warp time.
وهي قوية بما يكفي لتشوه الوقت.
I think this is the reason
أعتقد أن هذا هو السبب
the rescue team is not here yet.
فريق الإنقاذ ليس هنا بعد.
Yu,
يو ،
are you saying
هل تقول
they aren't able to come?
لا يستطيعون المجيء؟
I don't want to live on this island for the rest of my life.
لا أريد أن أعيش في هذه الجزيرة لبقية حياتي.
You'll be lucky if you can.
ستكون محظوظًا إذا استطعت.
The provisions from the boat
المؤن من القارب
are running out soon.
ينفد قريبا.
Calm down.
هدء من روعك.
Let's find a way together.
دعونا نجد طريقة معا.
We'll definitely be rescued.
سننقذ بالتأكيد.
That's easy for you to say.
أن من السهل عليك أن تقول.
What should we eat?
ماذا نأكل؟
Are we going to depend on your admirer to catch fish?
هل سنعتمد على معجبك في صيد السمك؟
Keep quiet.
الزم الصمت.
He's not reliable.
إنه غير موثوق.
If you want food,
إذا كنت تريد الطعام ،
I have plenty.
لدي الكثير.
It's better
من المفضل
to rely on me.
للاعتماد علي.
Were you the one who left the wrapper?
هل كنت من ترك الغلاف؟
Not only those.
ليس هؤلاء فقط.
I have plenty of food.
لدي الكثير من الطعام.
Let me go now.
اتركني اذهب الان.
If you don't, I won't share the food with you.
إذا لم تفعل ، فلن أشارك الطعام معك.
We'll let you go after you take us there.
سنسمح لك بالذهاب بعد أن تأخذنا إلى هناك.
This old woman is pretty suspicious.
هذه المرأة العجوز مشبوهة جدا.
Who are you calling an old woman?
من الذي تتصل بامرأة عجوز؟
I can take you there.
أستطيع أخذك هناك.
But
ولكن
I have one condition.
لدي شرط واحد.
What is it?
ما هذا؟
I want this girl to kiss me.
أريد هذه الفتاة أن تقبّلني.
Say that again.
قل ذلك مرة أخرى.
Stop fighting.
وقف القتال.
I'll kill you if you keep this on.
سأقتلك إذا واصلت هذا.
Enough!
كافية!
You're obsessed!
أنت مهووس!
Stop causing trouble.
توقف عن التسبب في المتاعب.
You want to kill me?
تريد قتلي؟
Just cut it out.
فقط اقطعها.
Then forget about the food.
ثم انسى الطعام.
All of you can die,
جميعكم يمكن أن يموتوا ،
and that'll be the end of it!
وستكون هذه نهاية الأمر!
You better respect my friends and me.
من الأفضل أن تحترمني وأصدقائي.
Or else, I won't be nice.
وإلا فلن أكون لطيفًا.
Okay.
تمام.
I was only kidding.
كنت امزح فقط.
Don't be mad.
لا تغضب.
I... I'll take you guys there.
أنا ... سآخذكم هناك يا رفاق.
Okay?
تمام؟
I'll take you guys there.
سآخذكم هناك يا رفاق.
Lead the way.
تقود الطريق.
Be careful.
كن حذرا.
Hurry up.
عجلوا.
Watch your head.
إنتبة لرأسك.
Be careful.
كن حذرا.
Mom, be careful.
أمي ، كوني حذرة.
It's so shabby.
إنه رث للغاية.
Where is it?
أين هي؟
The food is inside.
الطعام بالداخل.
How do we know
كيف نعرف
if you set up a trap in the cave?
إذا نصبت مصيدة في الكهف؟
The food is inside, in any case.
الطعام في الداخل ، على أي حال.
If you're not a coward, come with me.
إذا لم تكن جباناً ، تعال معي.
The men should go in first.
يجب أن يدخل الرجال أولاً.
Hurry up!
عجلوا!
It's inside.
إنه بالداخل.
Watch where you walk.
انتبه إلى أين تمشي.
Ying,
ينغ ،
be careful.
كن حذرا.
Are you sure the food is here?
هل أنت متأكد من أن الطعام هنا؟
What's your problem?
ما هي مشكلتك؟
Stop being rude to me.
توقف عن الوقاحة معي.
I have a name, you know?
لدي اسم، كما تعلمون؟
I can't believe this guy.
لا أصدق هذا الرجل.
May I know
هل لي أن أعلم
where's the food?
أين الطعام؟
That's more like it.
وهذا أشبه ذلك.
Since you asked,
منذ أن سألت ،
I'll be kind enough to tell you.
سأكون لطيفًا بما يكفي لأخبرك.
I woke up in this place.
استيقظت في هذا المكان.
I see this place as my house.
أرى هذا المكان بمثابة بيتي.
Without me,
من دوني،
you can't even find it.
لا يمكنك حتى العثور عليه.
Come along now.
تأتي على طول الآن.
Watch where you're going.
انتبه إلى أين أنت ذاهب.
Be careful.
كن حذرا.
There are many stones ahead.
أمامنا الكثير من الحجارة.
You have to be careful.
عليك أن تكون حذرا.
If he's a survivor of the shipwreck like us,
إذا كان أحد الناجين من حطام السفينة مثلنا
how did he
كيف فعل
end up in this cave?
في هذا الكهف؟
This guy says whatever he wants.
هذا الرجل يقول ما يريد.
We don't even know if he's telling the truth
لا نعرف حتى ما إذا كان يقول الحقيقة
or lying.
أو الكذب.
And did you notice
وهل لاحظت
this Chen Xingjian
هذا تشن Xingjian
does not look the same
لا تبدو متشابهة
as the one we met?
كالذي التقينا به؟
Yes.
نعم.
His manner of speaking and expression
طريقته في الكلام والتعبير
is like that of another person.
هو مثل شخص آخر.
He even saved me once.
لقد أنقذني مرة واحدة.
Chen Xingjian of the future is vile, cold-blooded,
تشن شينغ جيان من المستقبل هو حقير ، بدم بارد ،
and meticulous.
ودقيق.
He even provokes to infuriate us.
حتى أنه يثير حنقنا.
We were helpless against him.
كنا عاجزين ضده.
While this guy here
بينما هذا الرجل هنا
couldn't stand up straight when you frightened him.
لم يستطع الوقوف بشكل مستقيم عندما أخافته.
I know what you mean.
أنا أعرف ماذا تقصد.
But what did he experience
لكن ما الذي اختبره
that made him change drastically?
الذي جعله يتغير بشكل جذري؟
Do you still remember what Xu Jingmiao said
هل ما زلت تتذكر ما قاله شو جينغمياو
about another accomplice?
عن شريك آخر؟
Chen Xingjian was only an accessory to crime.
كان Chen Xingjian مجرد شريك في الجريمة.
The mastermind was someone else.
كان العقل المدبر شخصًا آخر.
Are you saying
هل تقول
that he's only following orders?
أنه يتبع الأوامر فقط؟
But even so,
ولكن على الرغم من ذلك،
his behavior shouldn't have such a drastic change.
لا ينبغي أن يكون لسلوكه مثل هذا التغيير الجذري.
Something is amiss here.
شيء ما خاطئ هنا.
Let me see what he's up to.
اسمحوا لي أن أرى ما ينوي القيام به.
Follow me.
اتبعني.
Be careful.
كن حذرا.
(What exactly makes)
(ما الذي يصنع بالضبط)
(a person)
(شخص)
(change into a completely different person?)
(التغيير إلى شخص مختلف تمامًا؟)
Are you troubled?
هل انت مضطربة؟
No.
رقم.
But I could feel
لكن يمكنني أن أشعر
you're very different
أنت مختلف جدا
from minutes ago.
منذ دقيقة.
I don't know
لا أعرف
why I feel that
لماذا أشعر بذلك
your life has changed a lot
لقد تغيرت حياتك كثيرا
in just a few minutes.
في غضون دقائق قليلة.
Just like these flowers.
تماما مثل هذه الزهور.
It seems like their time
يبدو أن وقتهم
was stolen away in an instant.
سرق في لحظة.
Sometimes, we would lose something.
في بعض الأحيان ، نفقد شيئًا ما.
But I think
لكنني أعتقد
we'll reunite what we lost
سنعيد ما فقدناه
at another time.
في وقت آخر.
Reunite at another time...
لم الشمل في وقت آخر ...
Since the universe lets you meet
منذ الكون يتيح لك اللقاء
over and over again,
مرارا وتكرارا،
it shows
يظهر
there's a strong and invisible attraction between you.
هناك جاذبية قوية وغير مرئية بينكما.
If one of you change,
إذا تغير أحدكم ،
the other one will change too.
سوف يتغير الآخر أيضًا.
I think that's the kind of connection you have.
أعتقد أن هذا هو نوع الاتصال الذي لديك.
Thanks.
شكرًا.
See?
نرى؟
I knew you were troubled.
كنت أعلم أنك كنت مضطربًا.
Let's go.
لنذهب.
Be careful.
كن حذرا.
Hurry up.
عجلوا.
It's up ahead.
إنه للأمام.
We're here!
نحن هنا!
These trunks are full of goods.
هذه الصناديق مليئة بالبضائع.
We have dry food and water.
لدينا طعام جاف وماء.
Gosh.
يا الهي.
There are so many of them.
هناك الكثير منهم.
We can hold on
يمكننا الصمود
until the rescue comes for us.
حتى يأتي الإنقاذ لنا.
See? I didn't lie.
نرى؟  أنا لم أكذب.
There are so many of us here.
يوجد الكثير منا هنا.
You better behave.
من الأفضل أن تتصرف.
Don't pull any tricks.
لا تسحب أي حيل.
I get no thanks at all.
أنا لا أحصل على شكر على الإطلاق.
Eat something.
كل شيئا.
I was wondering why didn't you want to eat.
كنت أتساءل لماذا لا تريد أن تأكل.
So you're hiding to eat all this yourself?
إذن أنت تختبئ لتأكل كل هذا بنفسك؟
What?
ماذا؟
I didn't have this on me.
لم يكن لدي هذا علي.
I took it out from here.
أخرجته من هنا.
See?
نرى؟
Just like this.
تماما مثل هذا.
Where did it go?
اين ذهبت؟
You...
أنت...
So it was you all along.
لذلك كنت أنت طوال الوقت.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
I didn't know
لم أكن أعرف
you could do magic tricks.
يمكنك عمل خدع سحرية.
Oh, this?
أوه ، هذا؟
If I weren't forced,
إذا لم أجبر ،
I wouldn't have learned it.
لم أكن لأتعلم ذلك.
What do you mean?
ماذا تقصد بذلك؟
Didn't you learn it out of interest?
ألم تتعلمها بدافع الاهتمام؟
Let's not talk about that.
دعنا لا نتحدث عن ذلك.
Tell me about yourself.
حدثني عن نفسك.
Here you are all alone.
هنا أنت وحيد.
But you're not taking good care of yourself.
لكنك لا تعتني بنفسك جيدًا.
Your family would be worried sick.
ستكون عائلتك مريضة قلقة.
Yeah.
نعم.
I guess they're worried about me.
أعتقد أنهم قلقون علي.
He... He's...
انه هو...
Are you from the Zhu Family?
هل أنت من عائلة Zhu؟
My last name is Zhu.
اسم عائلتي هو Zhu.
Of course, I'm from the Zhu Family.
بالطبع ، أنا من عائلة Zhu.
I'll go
سأذهب
and do some inventory count.
والقيام ببعض الجرد.
Have some water.
اشرب بعض الماء.
Thanks.
شكرًا.
No problem.
لا مشكلة.
I want to ask you something.
أريد أن أسألك شيئا.
Are you close with Chen Xingjian?
هل أنت مقرب من Chen Xingjian؟
What kind of person is he?
أي نوع من الأشخاص هو؟
He...
هو...
Let me show you this.
دعني أريك هذا.
I wrote the chorus
لقد كتبت الجوقة
for the song you wrote the other day.
للأغنية التي كتبتها في ذلك اليوم.
Take a look.
إلق نظرة.
Not bad, right?
ليس سيئا ، أليس كذلك؟
Let's do it.
لنفعلها.
(After we rise to popularity,)
(بعد أن نرتقي إلى الشعبية ،)
(we'll sell this song)
(سنبيع هذه الأغنية)
(to witness our talent and friendship.)
(لنشهد موهبتنا وصداقتنا.)
(You sold the song we wrote.)
(لقد بعت الأغنية التي كتبناها).
I didn't expect you'd even sell yourself.
لم أكن أتوقع حتى تبيع نفسك.
I know you quit working at the bar
أعلم أنك توقفت عن العمل في الحانة
to sign a contract with the influencer marketing company.
لتوقيع عقد مع شركة التسويق المؤثر.
Yes, I signed with them.
نعم ، لقد وقعت معهم.
The manager saw our performance.
رأى المدير أدائنا.
He said I'll be famous.
قال إنني سأكون مشهوراً.
After I become famous,
بعد أن أصبحت مشهوراً ،
we can fulfill...
يمكننا تحقيق ...
Cut the crap!
قطع الفضلات!
Fulfill what?
نفذ ماذا؟
Can you become famous?
هل يمكنك أن تصبح مشهوراً؟
You said it's for music.
قلت انها للموسيقى.
Why can't we try
لماذا لا نحاول
and change our concept for the sake of music?
ونغير مفهومنا من أجل الموسيقى؟
After I'm successful,
بعد أن نجحت ،
I'll sing whatever I want
سأغني ما أريد
and let those who like me
ودع من يحبونني
gradually like rock music.
بالتدريج مثل موسيقى الروك.
How is that bad?
كيف هذا سيء؟
You were tricked!
لقد تم خداعك!
You'll never have the chance!
لن تتاح لك الفرصة أبدًا!
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف.
I can do it.
أستطيع أن أفعل ذلك.
Zhou Wei,
تشو وي
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف.
I'm sorry, okay?
انا اسف اتفقنا
I don't care if you sold those songs.
لا يهمني إذا قمت ببيع تلك الأغاني.
We can write better ones.
يمكننا كتابة أفضل منها.
We have our audience.
لدينا جمهورنا.
We can already sing halftime now.
يمكننا بالفعل الغناء بين الشوطين الآن.
This is proof.
هذا دليل.
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف.
I want to give it a shot.
اريد ان اعطيها فرصة
You're a traitor if you leave!
أنت خائن إذا غادرت!
A traitor to music!
خائن للموسيقى!
I'll prove that I'm right.
سأثبت أنني على حق.
(How do I put this?)
(كيف أضع هذا؟)
He may be mean in his words.
قد يكون لئيمًا في كلماته.
But he's definitely a good guy.
لكنه بالتأكيد رجل جيد.
And he loves music very much.
وهو يحب الموسيقى كثيرا.
I think he's more talented than me.
أعتقد أنه موهوب أكثر مني.
So I think it was only a misunderstanding
لذلك أعتقد أنه كان مجرد سوء فهم
about him attacking Tan Jiao.
عنه مهاجمة تان جياو.
Wait here.
انتظر هنا.
Can I ask you something?
هل يمكننى ان اسألك شيئا؟
What are the odds?
ما هي احتمالات؟
I happened to have something to ask you too.
صادف أن لدي شيئًا أطلبه منك أيضًا.
We'll take turns, then.
سنتناوب ، إذن.
Deal.
صفقة.
You said you woke up in this cave.
قلت أنك استيقظت في هذا الكهف.
Was there anyone else here
هل كان هناك أي شخص آخر هنا
after you woke up?
بعد أن استيقظت؟
I did wake up
لقد استيقظت بالفعل
in this cave.
في هذا الكهف.
There wasn't anyone else.
لم يكن هناك أي شخص آخر.
My turn.
دوري.
I saved you.
أنا أنقذك.
But why did you say
لكن لماذا قلت
you want to kill me more than anyone else?
تريد قتلي أكثر من أي شخص آخر؟
Because you took someone important away from me.
لأنك أخذت شخصًا مهمًا بعيدًا عني.
Him?
له؟
These women are sure jealous.
هؤلاء النساء يشعرن بالغيرة بالتأكيد.
But don't worry.
لكن لا تقلق.
I like women.
احب النساء.
I have something else to ask.
لدي شيء آخر لأطلبه.
Why do you have so many questions?
لماذا لديك الكثير من الأسئلة؟
Are you Mr. Why?
هل انت سيد لماذا؟
Fine. Just ask.
بخير.  فقط إسأل.
I'm the Subor brand book reader device.
أنا جهاز قارئ كتب العلامة التجارية Subor.
You can pick anything you don't know, and I'll read it to you.
يمكنك اختيار أي شيء لا تعرفه ، وسأقرأه لك.
Since everyone
منذ الجميع
was washed up here by the waves,
جرفتها الأمواج هنا ،
why are you the only one
لماذا انت الوحيد
that ends up in this cave?
التي ينتهي بها المطاف في هذا الكهف؟
When I woke up, I was already in the cave.
عندما استيقظت ، كنت بالفعل في الكهف.
But not this cave.
لكن ليس هذا الكهف.
If you don't believe me,
إذا كنت لا تصدقني ،
I can take you there.
أستطيع أخذك هناك.
Something's weird.
شيء غريب.
I remember
أتذكر
there was a cave full of crystals nearby.
كان هناك كهف مليء بالبلورات في مكان قريب.
They're all gone now.
لقد ذهبوا جميعًا الآن.
What crystal cave?
ما الكهف البلوري؟
The whole cave
الكهف كله
is full of shiny stones.
مليء بالحجارة اللامعة.
I think they're pretty valuable.
أعتقد أنها ذات قيمة كبيرة.
Since we can't find them,
بما أننا لا نستطيع العثور عليهم ،
maybe they're on a different path.
ربما يكونون في طريق مختلف.
You said
أنت قلت
you were lying here when you woke up.
كنت تكذب هنا عندما استيقظت.
But there's no water around here.
لكن لا يوجد ماء هنا.
How did you get washed up here?
كيف اغتسلت هنا؟
How am I supposed to know?
كيف يفترض بي ان اعلم؟
Sleepwalking.
المشي أثناء النوم.
I'm sure it was sleepwalking.
أنا متأكد من أنه كان يسير أثناء النوم.
I dreamed I was at the beach.
حلمت أنني كنت على الشاطئ.
Then I slowly walked
ثم مشيت ببطء
to this place step by step.
إلى هذا المكان خطوة بخطوة.
Can you be more serious?
هل يمكنك أن تكون أكثر جدية؟
They're being serious here.
إنهم جادون هنا.
What's the point of making up stories like this?
ما الهدف من اختلاق مثل هذه القصص؟
Of course, there's a point.
بالطبع ، هناك نقطة.
It's better than looking for an agency to sign a contract.
إنه أفضل من البحث عن وكالة لتوقيع عقد.
Have you written a decent song after all these years?
هل كتبت أغنية لائقة بعد كل هذه السنوات؟
All the songs you write are repetitive.
كل الأغاني التي تكتبها متكررة.
It gets worse and worse.
انها تزداد سوءا.
You can insult me.
يمكنك أن تهينني.
But you can't insult my music!
لكن لا يمكنك إهانة موسيقاي!
So what if I insult you?
اذا ماذا لو اهنتك؟
I dare you to say that again!
أتحداك أن تقول ذلك مرة أخرى!
Are you trying to get physical?
هل تحاول أن تصبح جسديًا؟
- Are you... - I dare you to say that again!
- هل أنت ... - أتحداك أن تقول ذلك مرة أخرى!
You even want to raise your hand.
حتى أنك تريد أن ترفع يدك.
- Let me go! - Let him go.
- دعني أذهب!  - دعه يذهب.
You hit me.
أنت ضربتني.
So what if I did?
إذن ماذا لو فعلت؟
You're such a letdown.
يا لك من خيبة أمل.
I regretted being in a band with you!
ندمت على أن أكون في فرقة معك!
I...
أنا...
Stop fighting.
وقف القتال.
It's going to collapse.
سوف تنهار.
Tan Jiao!
تان جياو!
Wu Yu!
وو يو!
Tan Jiao. Tan Jiao.
تان جياو. تان جياو.
Tan Jiao!
تان جياو!
Check on the rest.
تحقق من الباقي.
I'll go and save Tan Jiao.
سأذهب وأنقذ تان جياو.
Okay.
تمام.
It's okay. I can do it myself.
حسنا.  أستطيع أن أفعل ذلك بنفسي.
Uh.
أوه.
Why haven't they come out yet?
لماذا لم يخرجوا بعد؟
What's wrong?
ما هو الخطأ؟
The cave collapsed.
انهار الكهف.
Where are the rest?
أين البقية؟
Where's Yu?
اين يو؟
Where are Wu Yu and Tan Jiao?
أين وو يو وتان جياو؟
Tan Jiao is trapped.
تان جياو محاصر.
Wu Yu went to save her.
ذهبت وو يو لإنقاذها.
(Wu Yu, calm down.)
(وو يو ، اهدأ.)
(She's waiting for you.)
(إنها تنتظرك).
I think it's no longer collapsing.
أعتقد أنه لم يعد ينهار.
Let's go and save them.
دعنا نذهب وننقذهم.
Okay.
تمام.
Be careful.
كن حذرا.
Wait.
انتظر.
It's dangerous inside.
إنه خطير في الداخل.
The girls should stay outside.
يجب على الفتيات البقاء في الخارج.
Yan Yuan,
يان يوان ،
please stay here to take care of the girls.
يرجى البقاء هنا لرعاية الفتيات.
Also, bring these things back to the campsite.
أيضًا ، أعد هذه الأشياء إلى موقع المخيم.
I'll go with Zhou Wei.
سأذهب مع Zhou Wei.
Be careful, okay?
كن حذرا ، حسنا؟
You must be careful.
يجب أن تكون حذرا.
Be careful.
كن حذرا.
Let's go.
لنذهب.
Come.
يأتي.
It's okay. I can carry it myself.
حسنا.  يمكنني حملها بنفسي.
Let me help you carry one.
دعني أساعدك في حمل واحدة.
Be careful.
كن حذرا.
Tan Jiao!
تان جياو!
Tan Jiao! Tan Jiao!
تان جياو! تان جياو!
Tan...
تان ...
Wu Yu.
وو يو.
Tan Jiao,
تان جياو ،
are you okay?
انت بخير؟
I'm fine.
أنا بخير.
Are you okay?
هل انت بخير؟
I'm okay too.
أنا بخير أيضًا.
I'm glad to hear that.
سعيد لسماع ذلك.
Just now,
الآن،
he blocked the rock for me.
لقد منع الصخرة من أجلي.
But he was knocked unconscious.
لكنه فقد وعيه.
How is he?
كيف حاله؟
He just passed out.
لقد أغمي عليه للتو.
Can you imagine
هل يمكنك أن تتخيل
in another time and space,
في زمان ومكان آخر ،
he killed my best friend,
لقد قتل أعز أصدقائي ،
your sister,
أختك،
and even wanted to kill me?
وحتى تريد قتلي؟
Yet, in this space and time,
ومع ذلك ، في هذا المكان والزمان ،
he rescued me twice.
أنقذني مرتين.
It's indeed hard to believe.
من الصعب حقا تصديق ذلك.
But seeing what happened on this island,
لكن رؤية ما حدث في هذه الجزيرة ،
he didn't seem to be putting up an act.
لا يبدو أنه يقوم بعمل ما.
The food can't be faked.
لا يمكن تزوير الطعام.
And he cannot predict
ولا يمكنه التنبؤ
our every move
كل خطوة لدينا
and accident that happens.
والحادث الذي يحدث.
All these can't be arranged in advance.
كل هذه لا يمكن ترتيبها مسبقا.
But I feel conflicted.
لكني أشعر بالتضارب.
I don't know how to face someone
لا أعرف كيف أواجه شخصًا ما
who will kill Xiaoyu
من سيقتل شياويو
and many innocent girls in the future.
والعديد من الفتيات الأبرياء في المستقبل.
I even...
أنا حتى...
I even
أنا حتى
helped him bandage his wound just now.
ساعده في تضميد جرحه الآن.
You did the right thing.
فعلت الشيء الصحيح.
If Xiaoyu were here,
إذا كان شياويو هنا ،
she'd do the same thing.
كانت ستفعل نفس الشيء.
But I feel so uneasy.
لكني أشعر بعدم الارتياح.
Even if Chen Xingjian is innocent at this moment,
حتى لو كان Chen Xingjian بريئًا في هذه اللحظة ،
are we going
نحن ذاهبون
to watch him
لمشاهدته
turn into a heinous killer?
تتحول إلى قاتل شنيع؟
We're indulging him
نحن ننغمس معه
and supporting him in his crime.
ودعمه في جريمته.
So is everything you said just now
هذا هو كل ما قلته الآن
real?
حقا؟
♪May time flies♪
♪ قد يطير الوقت
♪May you appear before me♪
♪ قد تظهر أمامي ♪
♪May you hold my hands♪
♪ أرجو أن تمسك يدي ♪
♪As you take the oath♪
كما تحلف اليمين
♪May you live a thousand years♪
♪ أتمنى أن تعيش ألف سنة ♪
♪May you live a life full of love♪
♪ عسى أن تعيش حياة مليئة بالحب
♪May your heart skip a beat♪
♪ قد يتخطى قلبك الخفقان ♪
♪Whenever you meet me♪
متى تقابلني ♪
♪May you have a space♪
♪ قد يكون لديك مساحة
♪To watch my previous love life♪
♪ لمشاهدة حياتي العاطفية السابقة ♪
♪May you have clairvoyance♪
♪ قد يكون لديك استبصار ♪
♪To see when we will meet♪
لنرى متى سنلتقي
♪The fish and the bird♪
السمكة والعصفور
♪Who is meeting whom♪
♪ من يلتقي بمن ♪
♪How deep does our love go and whose life will be spent?♪
ما مدى عمق حبنا ومن ستمضي حياته؟
♪The cloud and the moon♪
♪ السحابة والقمر ♪
♪Who runs into whom?♪
♪ من يصطدم بمن؟
♪Flowers bloom and wilt as time passes by♪
تتفتح الأزهار وتذبل بمرور الوقت ♪
♪May you live a thousand years♪
♪ أتمنى أن تعيش ألف سنة ♪
♪May you live a life full of love♪
♪ عسى أن تعيش حياة مليئة بالحب
♪May your heart skip a beat♪
♪ قد يتخطى قلبك الخفقان ♪
♪Whenever you meet me♪
متى تقابلني ♪
♪May you travel far and wide♪
قد تسافر بعيدًا وواسعًا ♪
♪To witness all flavors of love♪
لتشهد كل نكهات الحب ♪
♪May you travel with me♪
♪ قد تسافر معي ♪
♪For the blissful moments to come♪
للحظات الهناء القادمة ♪
♪The cloud and the moon♪
♪ السحابة والقمر ♪
♪Who is meeting whom♪
♪ من يلتقي بمن ♪
♪How deep does our love go and whose life will be spent?♪
ما مدى عمق حبنا ومن ستمضي حياته؟
♪The fish and the bird♪
السمكة والعصفور
♪Who runs into whom?♪
♪ من يصطدم بمن؟
♪Flowers bloom and wilt as time passes by♪
تتفتح الأزهار وتذبل بمرور الوقت ♪
♪The cloud and the moon♪
♪ السحابة والقمر ♪
♪Whose and whose oath is it?♪
لمن هذا اليمين؟
♪How deep does our love go and whose attachment is this?♪
ما مدى عمق حبنا ومن هذا الارتباط؟
♪The fish and the bird♪
السمكة والعصفور
♪Whose and whose trial of love is this?♪
لمن هذه ومحبة من هذه؟
♪Flowers bloom and wilt as we shine in time♪
تتفتح الأزهار وتذبل مع تألقنا بمرور الوقت ♪